<!-- LB -->

<item>
<title>Whole</title>
<guid>https://davidraji.com/blog.html/blog.html#whole</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 23:38:11 -0700</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[
<p><b>The Question: </b>Of all the diets, which is the healthiest and the best for living long and healing?</p>
<p><b>Summary:</b> This book uses the scientific method to convince the reader that raw plant based food is the best for health.
There is a China study especially where the whole raw plant based diet showed incredible results in helping people with
chronic health issues.</p>
<p><b>Fascinating Idea:</b> This book made some insaaaane claims about the healing properties of whole plant-based diets.
Reversing diabetes, curing cancers, reducing seizures just miracle cure levels of healing and did a decent job pointing
to scientific papers that backed it’s ideas. Needs some research</p>
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Becoming</title>
<guid>https://davidraji.com/blog.html/blog.html#becoming</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 23:04:29 -0700</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[
<p><b>Question:</b> Who is Michelle Obama?</p> 
<p><b>Summary:</b> Michelle Obama is a badass, but she’s also just a woman that’s trying her best. She does a great job telling us
about her upbringing and showing us a deeply relatable version of her life story. Honestly, reading this book made me
realize that most people that I look up to are incredibly lucky, normal and approachable. Barack seemed like such a
force of nature tho.</p>
<p><b>Fascinating Idea: </b>The book emphasizes a commitment to trying your best and also being transparent about failures. One
major takeaway about Michelle’s life is that you don’t have to be perfect to be good and have a great impact in the
world. Sometimes even our heroes are just people trying their best.</p>
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Your Money or Your Life</title>
<guid>https://davidraji.com/blog.html/blog.html#your-money-or-your-life</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 18:35:59 -0700</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[
<p><b> The Question:</b> How do I get a better relationship with money? </p>
<p><b>Summary:</b> The last budgeting book that you’ll ever need. It approaches budgeting by asking you how much money you really need. Then it starts getting philosophical in it’s questions about your life, what you really want and how you want to live. The book explains that money is a tool and that it’s main purpose is to give you the life you want. So it implores you to think about cutting out the excess in your life and focus it on true financial freedom which is having the freedom to do exactly what you want with your time. </p>
<p><b>Fascinating idea:</b> That money is interchangeable with life energy. 
You want to be doing exactly what you want with you life and financial freedom is understanding that and being free from vocational obligations
</p>
]]></description>
</item>

