<!-- LB -->

<item>
<title>Talking to Strangers - Malcolm Gladwell</title>
<guid>https://davidraji.com/blog.html/blog.html#talking-to-strangers-malcolm-gladwell</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 01:19:26 -0700</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[
<p><b>The Question:</b> Do we actually understand strangers and how can we better judge people we don’t know?</p>
<p><b>Summary:</b> When talking to strangers we make quite a bit of assumptions that we wouldn’t make about ourselves. We’re
overconfident in how well we can judge strangers and that leads to gross misjudgements of character. The book goes
through many examples breaking down how we’re often wrong and the biases that make us wrong.</p>
<p><b>Fascinating Idea:</b> So many good ones in this book. How police investigators/FBI agents who are tasked to discover lies
are most gullible when people’s emotions don’t match their expressions. Due to this, it’s sometimes more reliable to use
raw data to judge character instead of the reputation/expectations of someone tasked with interviewing a stranger.</p>
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>You and Me Forever</title>
<guid>https://davidraji.com/blog.html/blog.html#you-and-me-forever</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 01:15:22 -0700</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[
<p><b>The Question:</b> How can I have a solid Christian marriage?</p>
<p><b>Summary:</b> This is the book on Christian marriage by Francis Chan. The man is known for just owning the phrase “to live is
Christ and to die is gain”. All about going all out. The book, and virtual workshop walk through practical steps to
strengthen and rebuild your marriage centered on Christ.</p>
<p><b>Fascinating Idea:</b> The most important thing in your relationship is both of your relationships with God and his mission
to make disciples. If you’re having marriage problems, you’re probably having Jesus problems. It’s main takeaway is that
you should band together and focus on pursuing Christ and make much of Him to improve your marriage as a byproduct.</p>
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>The Road Back to You</title>
<guid>https://davidraji.com/blog.html/blog.html#the-road-back-to-you</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 01:06:33 -0700</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[
<p><b>The Question:</b> How do we fit into our personality types and how does that inform our interactions?</p>
<p><b>Summary:</b> This is a book about the Enneagram. The book goes through each of the personality types and evaluates what
they’re like in childhood, under stress, when calm and safe. The book also gives famous examples with that personality
type, and makes predictions about how someone may be like at work or in a relationship. This is meant to help you see
your tendencies and better identify which personality type you adhere to.</p>
<p><b>Fascinating Idea: </b>The idea that taking the personality test might be misleading. According to this book, when you take
the personality test, you sometimes answer in a way that is expected of you or what you want to be. I understand that
because as I read the descriptions, I saw myself in different personalities than just in the one that fit me best.</p>
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Utopia for Realists</title>
<guid>https://davidraji.com/blog.html/blog.html#utopia-for-realists</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:50:59 -0700</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[
<p><b>The Question:</b> Can we build a better, more equitable world purely based on science?</p>
<p><b>Summary:</b> This book assesses what it’s like to build a Utopian state through idealistic governance. Mainly focuses on
universal basic income, shorter work weeks and open borders. This book evaluates ways to implement these ideals and
why/how it might contribute to creating utopia.</p>
<p><b>Fascinating Idea:</b> Universal basic income for all people seems to be the books most daring and pertinent topic. It’s
presenting the argument and using cases from around the world to justify it. From GiveDirectly’s work in rural Kenya and
even a Canadian experiment in a small Manitoban community.</p>
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Americanah</title>
<guid>https://davidraji.com/blog.html/blog.html#americanah</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:50:02 -0700</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[
<p><b>The Question: </b>Who is Ifemelu and how can you marry her American and Nigerian identities?</p>
<p><b>Summary:</b> A high-energy, full personality Nigerian woman, Ifemelu, moves to America. Difficulties and complexities of
life ensue. Then moves back to Nigeria as grown-up Americanah. In addition to cultural touchstone it doubles as a
complex love story.</p>
<p><b>Fascinating Idea: </b>There’s a lot of loves in this book and as confident and bombastic the main character is, she suffers
from a lack of self-reflection. In a lot of the instances, I found myself being sympathetic to the people and families
that were hurt along the way from reckless behaviour in pursuit of feelings.</p>
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>The Sacred Search</title>
<guid>https://davidraji.com/blog.html/blog.html#the-sacred-search</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:48:40 -0700</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[
<p><b>The Question:</b> What’s the right way to date as a Christian person?</p>
<p><b>Summary:</b> A knowledgeable assessment of Christian dating. The subject of many a disgruntled believer. If the bible talks
a big game about marriage, what does it say about dating?</p>
<p><b>Fascinating Idea:</b> Christian dating is evaluating whether this person is someone that you can marry. Being very diligent
in the task of assessing if they can be there through life’s twists and turns. You might do everything right, follow the
guidance to the letter and things might still fall apart. That’s why the most important part is prayer.</p>
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title></title>
<guid>https://davidraji.com/blog.html/blog.html#factfulness</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:46:37 -0700</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[
<p><b>The Question:</b> What is an up-to-date snapshot of International Development?</p>
<p><b>Summary:</b> This is a book about world facts. What is the actual state of world development in 2019. The writer explains
in-depth how we are all relying on outdated misconceptions about how poor the global south is and this book does an up
to date assessment on where people are at in global development.</p>
<p><b>Fascinating Idea:</b> That the idea of ‘developed’ countries and ‘developing’ countries is outdated. Instead there’s a 4
tiered system that better breaks down wealth from the absolute poorest to ‘middle income’ countries and then rich
countries. Most people are actually in the top half, vase majority in the top 3 with a few billion in abject poverty.
Also even within so-called ‘rich’ countries, you find people across that spectrum (usually the top two tiers).</p>
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>The Ruthless Elimination of Hurry</title>
<guid>https://davidraji.com/blog.html/blog.html#the-ruthless-elimination-of-hurry</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:42:12 -0700</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[
<p><b>The Question:</b> How can I live a more rested life and avoid burnout?</p>
<p><b>Summary:</b> This book gives the argument for slowing down in life. It breaks down the dangers of hurry and how it hurts us,
our lives and our faith. Then goes through practical steps on slowing down. There’s no rush. You’ll make less mistakes
and it makes everyday life so much more manageable.</p>
<p><b>Fascinating Idea:</b> One of the ideas in this book is just incorporating the lack of hurry into everyday life. General
patience. Not jay-walking, not checking your phone when waiting in line for a sec, breathing slow, arriving early,
walking/biking instead of driving. Reading the book in itself was a leisure endeavor and it really biblically sold me on
this lifestyle of calm and leisure.</p>
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Spiritual Leadership</title>
<guid>https://davidraji.com/blog.html/blog.html#spiritual-leadership</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:41:11 -0700</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[
<p><b>The Question:</b> What makes a good spiritual leader and how can I become one?</p>
<p><b>Summary:</b> This is a great, simple and straight-forward book on leadership. I found it relevant to all leadership, not
just spiritual leadership. Breaks down leadership principles and methods of thinking about them.</p>
<p><b>Fascinating Idea:</b> Lots of good nuggets here. Big ones that I felt I needed to be reminded of time and again is prayer,
delegation and pride. Prayer as a tool to prepare for what you can’t see and just to involve God in your life. When you
micromanage and refuse to delegate, you’re robbing someone of the opportunity to grow and yourself of the opportunity to
have rest. Pride is just the downfall of even the best leader.</p>
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Whole</title>
<guid>https://davidraji.com/blog.html/blog.html#whole</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 23:38:11 -0700</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[
<p><b>The Question: </b>Of all the diets, which is the healthiest and the best for living long and healing?</p>
<p><b>Summary:</b> This book uses the scientific method to convince the reader that raw plant based food is the best for health.
There is a China study especially where the whole raw plant based diet showed incredible results in helping people with
chronic health issues.</p>
<p><b>Fascinating Idea:</b> This book made some insaaaane claims about the healing properties of whole plant-based diets.
Reversing diabetes, curing cancers, reducing seizures just miracle cure levels of healing and did a decent job pointing
to scientific papers that backed it’s ideas. Needs some research</p>
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Becoming</title>
<guid>https://davidraji.com/blog.html/blog.html#becoming</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 23:04:29 -0700</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[
<p><b>Question:</b> Who is Michelle Obama?</p> 
<p><b>Summary:</b> Michelle Obama is a badass, but she’s also just a woman that’s trying her best. She does a great job telling us
about her upbringing and showing us a deeply relatable version of her life story. Honestly, reading this book made me
realize that most people that I look up to are incredibly lucky, normal and approachable. Barack seemed like such a
force of nature tho.</p>
<p><b>Fascinating Idea: </b>The book emphasizes a commitment to trying your best and also being transparent about failures. One
major takeaway about Michelle’s life is that you don’t have to be perfect to be good and have a great impact in the
world. Sometimes even our heroes are just people trying their best.</p>
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Your Money or Your Life</title>
<guid>https://davidraji.com/blog.html/blog.html#your-money-or-your-life</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 18:35:59 -0700</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[
<p><b> The Question:</b> How do I get a better relationship with money? </p>
<p><b>Summary:</b> The last budgeting book that you’ll ever need. It approaches budgeting by asking you how much money you really need. Then it starts getting philosophical in it’s questions about your life, what you really want and how you want to live. The book explains that money is a tool and that it’s main purpose is to give you the life you want. So it implores you to think about cutting out the excess in your life and focus it on true financial freedom which is having the freedom to do exactly what you want with your time. </p>
<p><b>Fascinating idea:</b> That money is interchangeable with life energy. 
You want to be doing exactly what you want with you life and financial freedom is understanding that and being free from vocational obligations
</p>
]]></description>
</item>

